

Turin, Italy +39 380 754 0657 mohamadusama242@gmail.com

# Mohamad Usama KUNNATHUR

**DevOps Engineer** 

https://github.com/usama242 https://www.linkedin.com/in/usama242/ https://kunnathur.tech/

#### **ABOUT**

A DevOps and Cloud Engineer with more than two years of experience in building, automating and maintaining Cloud infrastructure and environment. A quick learner, team player, and multi-skilled (check the <u>website</u>) interested in Al. A background in Management & Engineering means I bring a unique perspective to the team.

#### **SKILLS**

**Proficient:** AWS (EC2, VPC, S3, SQS, SNS, etc), Python, JavaScript (NodeJS, TypeScript, etc), Linux, IaC (Cloudformation & Terraform), CI/CD (Bamboo, Gitlab, Azure Pipelines)

**Moderate:** Azure (VM, Pipeline, CLI, Policy, etc), Docker, Kubernetes, Postman, Selenium, Jmeter, Database (DynamoDB, MySQL, Elasticsearch, etc)

#### **EXPERIENCE**

Idea 75, Bari, Italy - DevOps Engineer

Oct 2022 - PRESENT

- Working on Identity products such as SPID, Gosign, etc.
- Orchestrating containerization for legacy application modernization
- Migrating on-premises applications to cloud platforms
- Administering databases and overseeing observability measures

Idea 75, Bari, Italy - DevOps Engineer

Oct 2022 - PRESENT

- Facilitate deployment automation and CI/CD. Monitoring and observability.
- Reduce bottlenecks (Build times, latency) and optimize costs (Rescaling resources)
- Ensure zero downtime and high availability (Load balancing & autoscaling resources)

Reply, Turin, Italy - Cloud Developer

MAY 2020 - OCT 2022

- Developed lambda functions and facilitated pipeline automation
- Troubleshooting and fixing errors. Test automation (Functional, UI, Performance)
- Recommended redimensioning of resources saving \$10k / month

# PROJECTS (BOSCH AI ACCELERATOR PROGRAM)

# Deploying a scalable laaS web server in Azure (link)

- Using Terraform to create infrastructures like Virtual Networks, Virtual Machines, etc.
- Creating a custom VM Image using Packer and then deploying it in VMs

# Building a CI/CD pipeline (link)

- Cl using GitHub Actions to automate unit testing and linting to keep the code prod ready
- CD using Azure Pipelines which builds and deploys a Flask app to Azure App Service

# Ensuring quality releases (link)

- Automated testing like API (Postman), Functional UI (Selenium) & Performance (Jmeter)
- Also configuring Custom Log ingestion & Custom Alarm metrics.

# Techtrends: Container Orchestration (link)

- GitHub actions to create a custom Docker image and push it to DockerHub
- Vagrant to provision a custom virtual machine environment in VirtualBox
- Deploy an app to a Kubernetes cluster using Helm chart & ArgoCD

#### Best coding practices and unit test (link)

- Refactoring a Jupyter notebook into Python code using best coding practices.
- This involves precise documentation, adhering to pep8 specs & unit tests.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Bosch Al Talent Accelerator Program (Udacity, Online)** - DevOps Engineer

JULY 2022 - NOV 2022

- Experienced infrastructure automation with hands-on projects.
- Followed clean code principles and focussed on cloud-native apps

#### **Udacity, Online** - Front-End Web Development

JAN 2020 - MAR 2020

- Focus on CSS, JavaScript, APIs, Build tools & Express—NodeJS for the backend.
- Front-end libraries such as React. The projects can be found on my GitHub

#### Politecnico di Torino, Turin, Italy - M.S Engineering & Management

SEP 2017 - MAR 2020

- Learned about Information Systems, project, and data management
- Thesis on "Applying Al Techniques on Project Management" (link)

### THK University, Ankara, Turkey - B.S Aeronautical Engineering

SEP 2012 - JUNE 2016

- Concentration in Aerodynamics, FEM & CAD
- Academic internship on solving Navier-stokes equation using Python

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in the application to be processed for the purposes of recruitment/internal process